Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 1064 records 1937-1997 IBT0037
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Local 1064 records
1937-1997
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
IBT0037
3.75 Linear Feet
This collection contains a variety of material relating to IBT Local 1064 of Billings, MT, dating from 1937-1997. While most of the materials were produced directly by Local 1064, the collection also contains materials from its predecessor, AFL Federal Labor Union 18741, as well as IBT Local 190, with whom Local 1064 merged in the 1990s. Included are correspondence, financial reports, seniority lists, dues ledgers, IBT directories and rosters, union constitutions and by-laws, labor agreements, newsletters and newspapers, meeting minutes and roll-call books.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 2012 [2012.085].
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains a variety of records relating to IBT Local 1064 of Billings, MT, dating from 1937-1997. Most of the materials were produced directly by Local 1064. The collection also contains materials from two other organizations: 1064's predecessor, Federal Labor Union 18741 of the American Federation of Labor and from IBT Local 190, a separate local that merged with 1064 in the 1990s. Included are correspondence, financial reports, seniority lists, dues ledgers, IBT directories and rosters, union constitutions and by-laws, labor agreements, newsletters and newspapers, meeting minutes, and roll-call books.
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions; Labor; Contracts; Collective labor agreements; Labor unions -- Montana -- History -- 20th century
- General Files, 1937-1997; Series 1; 2 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a variety of material relating to IBT Local 1064 of Billings, MT, dating from 1937-1997. While most of the materials were produced directly by Local 1064, the series also contains materials from its predecessor, AFL Federal Labor Union 18741, as well as IBT Local 190, with whom Local 1064 merged in the 1990s. Included are correspondence, financial reports, seniority lists, dues ledgers, IBT directories and rosters, union constitutions and by-laws, labor agreements, newsletters and newspapers, and other miscellaneous material.
  - Ballots, 1990; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1955; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1990; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board Meetings, 1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Financial Statements and Auditor's Reports, 1980-1986; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Great Western Sugar Company, 1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Great Western Sugar Company Insurance Plans, 1954-1985; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Great Western Sugar Company Pension Information, 1976-1979; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Great Western Sugar Company Pension Information, 1975-1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Grievances, 1977-1982; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hold-Over, Seniority and Dues Lists, 1941-1987; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hold-Over, Seniority and Dues Lists, 1961-1989; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - IBT Directories, 1987-1989; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - IBT Local 190 Constitution and By-Laws, 1957; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - IBT Local 190 Dues Ledger, 1937-1940; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - IBT Local 190 Dues Ledger, 1949-1950; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - IBT Local 1064 Constitution and By-Laws, 1955-1980; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - IBT Local 1064 Incorporation / AFL Federal Labor Union 18741 Dissolution, 1954; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - IBT Meeting Ritual, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - IBT Rosters, 1972-1983; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - IBT Rosters, 1983-1987; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - IBT Rosters, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Inter-Factory Council of Sugar Workers, 1952-1955; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Inter-State Council of Sugar Workers, 1973-1985; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Inter-State Council of Sugar Workers Financial Reports, 1986-1989; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Labor Agreements, 1953-1964; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Labor Agreements, 1967-1981; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Labor Agreements, 1984-1989; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Labor Agreements, 1961-1989; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Labor Agreements, 1989; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Life With Dues Program, 1964-1971; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Montana State Federation of Labor Year Book, 1954; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Montana State Sugar Beet Committee, 1952; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters and Newspapers, 1964-1997; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Non-Communist Union Officer Affidavits, 1957; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Official Election Reports, 1969-1990; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Safety Meetings, 1946-1954; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Sugar World" Newsletter, 1985-1990; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "The Teamster Sugar Worker" Newsletter, 1988-1990; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Teamsters Death Benefit Trust Fund, 1989; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters Certificate of Affiliation, 1955 April 1; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Western Conference of Teamsters By-Laws, 1961; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Yellowstone Country Trades & Labor Assembly, 1939-1955; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1945-1991; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Meeting Minutes and Roll Call Books, 1938-1990; Series 2; 1.75 Linear Feet
  This series contains hand-written and typed meeting minutes and roll-call books from IBT Locals 1064 and 1068, as well as their predecessors, AFL Federal Labor Unions 18741 and 21731. Also included are meeting minutes of the Inter-Factory Council of Sugar Workers and the Inter-State Council of Sugar Workers, two regional labor organizations which included IBT Locals 1064 and 1068. The materials date from 1938 to 1990.
  - AFL Federal Labor Union 18741 Meeting Minutes, 1938-1946; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AFL Federal Labor Union 18741 Meeting Minutes, 1945-1950; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AFL Federal Labor Union 18741 Meeting Minutes, 1950-1954; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AFL Federal Labor Union 18741 Roll Call Book, 1944 September 27 - 1953 June 3; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AFL Federal Labor Union 18741 / IBT Local 1064 Roll Call Book, 1953 June 10 - 1960 January 13; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AFL Federal Labor Union 21731 Meeting Minutes, 1942 November 23 - 1949 November 30; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AFL Federal Labor Union 21731 Meeting Minutes, 1950 January 27 - 1954 August 6; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1954-1956; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1957-1959; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1960-1962; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1963-1967; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1968-1972; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1973-1978; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1979-1983; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1984-1988; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - IBT Local 1064 Meeting Minutes, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - IBT Local 1064 Roll Call Book, 1960-1972; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - IBT Local 1064 Roll Call Book, 1972-1977; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - IBT Local 1064 Roll Call Book, 1977-1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - IBT Local 1064 Roll Call Book, 1982-1986; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - IBT Local 1064 Roll Call Book, 1986-1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - IBT Local 1064 Roll Call of Officers, 1980-1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - IBT Local 1068 Meeting Minutes, 1954-1959; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - IBT Local 1068 Meeting Minutes, 1960-1968; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - IBT Local 1068 Meeting Minutes, 1968-1984; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - IBT Local 1068 Meeting Minutes, 1985-1990; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Inter-Factory Council of Sugar Workers Meeting Minutes, 1954-1974; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Inter-State Council of Sugar Workers Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Inter-State Council of Sugar Workers Meeting Minutes, 1980-1984; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)